DIMITRA GIANTSIDI

https://dgiantsidi.github.io/ · dimitra.giantsidi@gmail.com Informatics Forum 1.05, University of Edinburgh 10 Crichton Street, EH8 9AB, Edinburgh, United Kingdom

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I like to build robust and efficient distributed systems!

I am a final year PhD student at the University of Edinburgh, UK and as part of my research, I have worked on some interesting projects: a secure distributed transactional store (Trusted Execution Environments, RDMA and RocksDB), a shielded direct I/O network library for secure replication (Crash Fault Tolerance and BFT) and a fast shared log for serverless computing infrastuctures (byte addressable storage, gRPC/TCP). I am currently designing a trusted NIC architecture for large-scale distributed systems based on SmartNICs.

EDUCATION

PhD in Computer Science

Sept 2019 - present

University of Edinburgh, UK

- · Sponsors: Microsoft Research, UK Rise, Advisor: Prof. Dr. Pramod Bhatotia
- · Distributed systems, systems security, replication protocols

 \mathbf{MSc} in Computer Science

Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

University of Edinburgh, UK

· Best Performing Female MSc Thesis Award

MEng in Computer and Electrical Engineering

Sept 2012 - Feb 2018

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA), Greece

EMPLOYMENT

Microsoft Research, Cambridge, UK

Sept 2021 - Dec 2021

Research Scientist Intern

· Design of KVs for timing attacks.

University of Edinburgh, UK

June 2023 - present

 $Research\ Assistant$

· Hardware/software co-design of a trusted NIC architecture.

Intracom Telecom, Athens, Greece

Jul 2017 - Jul 2018

 $Software \ \& \ Systems \ Engineer$

· Performance and energy optimization of NFV services.

Unversity of Edinburgh, UK and TUM, Germany

Sept 2019 - present

Thesis advisor and Teaching Assistant

- · Operating Systems, Distributed Computing, Parallel Architectures, Object-oriented Programming.
- \cdot Supervised five BSc/MSc students on their BSc Thesis on Distributed and Networking systems.

PUBLICATIONS

Anchor: Secure Persistent Memory Architecture, SIGMOD'24

Dimitris Stravakakis, Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Philip Saendig, Shady Issa, Pramod Bhatotia.

FlexLog: A Shared Log for Stateful Serverless Computing, ACM HPDC'23

 $\label{eq:continuity} \mbox{Dimitra Giantsidi, Emmanouil Giortamis, Nathaniel Tornow, Florin Dinu, Pramod Bhatotia.}$

Treaty: Secure Distributed Transactions, IEEE/IFIP DSN'22 (Best paper nominee)

Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Natacha Crooks, Pramod Bhatotia.

Avocado: A Secure In-Memory Distributed Storage System, USENIX ATC'21

Maurice Bailleu, Dimitra Giantsidi, Vasilis Gavrielatos, Le Quoc Do, Vijay Nagarajan, Pramod Bhatotia.

DICER: Diligent Cache Partitioning for Efficient Workload Consolidation, ICPP'19

Konstantinos Nikas, Nikela Papadopoulou, Dimitra Giantsidi, Vasileios Karakostas, Georgios Goumas, Nectarios Koziris.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages C/C++, Python, Bash, Golang, Java, Vitis HLS

Systems Programming RocksDB and folly libraries, TEEs (Intel SGX, OpenEnclave SDK, AMD-sev),

direct network I/O (DPDK, RDMA, Alveo SmartNICs), SPDK,

Intel RDT, LLVM, collectd, POSIX/Unix, OpenMP and MPI, gRPC

Virtualization KVM, Qemu/Libvirt, Docker, Kubernetes

Version Control Git

Distributed Programming Hadoop MapReduce, Socket and RPC programming

HONORS AND AWARDS

PhD scolarship, Microsoft Research	2019
Research Grant, BaCaTec	2021
Claire Jones Prize, Adelard Prize for Best Performing Female MSc Student at the University of Edinburgh	2019
Highest Honors award Top 0.1% in national qualification exams, GPA: 19.6/20	2012